Walt Kuhn Family Papers and Armory Show
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Walt Kuhn Family Papers, 1859-1978, Series 4:; (Box 3-26, 32-35, OV 39-55; 25.8 linear feet)
  - General Correspondence, 1890-1966, 4.3:; (Box 5-9, 32, OV 40; 4 linear feet)
    The following is a selective index to correspondents represented in 4.3: General Correspondence, with cross-references to correspondence in 4.4: Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files and 4.5: Provenance Files. It is not comprehensive. An effort has been made to index regionally and nationally known artists, Kuhn's patrons and students, models, art historians, writers, museum and gallery staff, dealers, and persons known to be well-represented in other collections at the Archives of American Art. Cross-references to existing letters in other parts of the Kuhn papers and Armory Show records are included selectively. Correspondents who have not been indexed include family members, neighbors, business contacts from his theater and vaudeville work of the early 1920s, and from his railroad car design work from 1936 to 1948.
    Abeel, Neilson (American-Scandinavian Foundation): 1930 (3 letters)
    Abercrombie and Fitch: 1948-1949 (4 letters)
    Adair, William Gleason: 1945
    Adams, Philip R. (Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts): 1938-1946, 1948-1951 (51 letters; See also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Adams, Ruth Hutchins: 1943-1944 (6 letters)
    Albany Institute of History and Art (see MacFarlane)
    Aldis, Graham: 1928
    American Print Makers (see also Goldsmith, B.K.): 1928 (2 letters)
    American Federation of the Arts: 1950 (see also N. Anderson, Messer, Pope, Prior, E. Spaeth)
    Ames, Mary (Mrs. John W.; see Goodyear, Mary)
    Ames, Winslow (Lyman Allyn Museum): 1934 (3 letters)
    Anderson, Nesta (Mrs. A. Scott; American Federation of Arts): 1951-1952 (3 letters)
    Anderson, Sherwood: 1928, undated (2 letters)
    Angle, Catherine (Mrs. Everett E.; Nebraska Art Association): 1946
    Anisfeld, Mara: 1932
    Arden Gallery (see Meigs and Smoluchowska)
    Arensberg, Walter C.: 1938 (see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Armory Show 50th Anniversary Exhibition (Winslow Carlton): 1963 (see also Henry Street Settlement)
    Arnold, Grace (Mrs. Harry Bartley): 1941, 1945 (3 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Art Students League of New York: 1927
    Arts Club of Chicago: 1927, 1934, 1956 (6 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Asherman, David: 1936, undated (2 letters including Christmas card with original, signed print)
    Austin, Darrel (see also Perls): 1940, 1941 (4 letters)
    Bahr, A.W. (Billy): 1923, 1938, 1945, 1947-1949 (7 letters)
    Balkan, Edward Duff: 1932
    Ballin, Hugo: 1937 (2 letters)
    Bangsbergh, Raymond: 1939
    Barber, George R.: 1933
    Barr, Alfred H. Jr. (Museum of Modern Art): 1929, 1934, 1945 (5 letters)
    Barrie, Erwin S. (Grand Central Art Galleries): 1927, 1951 (5 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Barrington, Lewis: 1932
    Barry, Bobby (see Provenance Files, "Portrait of Bobby Barry")
    Bartlett, Frederic Clay, Jr.: 1939-1940, 1942-1943, 1945, 1947 (7 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Bartley, Louise: 1931
    Baur, John I.H. (Brooklyn Museum): 1946 (see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Beals, Ralph A. (New York Public Library): 1949
    Bear, Donald (Santa Barbara Museum of Art): 1936-1938, 1945, 1948, 1949 (6 items including Christmas cards with original prints; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Beerbohm, Marvin (Detroit School of Art): 1938
    Bell, Janet M. (John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art): 1952 (4 letters)
    Belmont, Eleanor R.: 1935 Benjamin, Ruth: 1940
    Bernays, Edward L. (see also Doris E. Fleischman): 1928, 1935-1937 (4 letters)
    Bernhardt, John: 1948-1950 (4 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files, 1947)
    Beuf, Carlo: 1928
    Bidwell, Watson (Denver Art Museum): 1936-1940, 1945, 1947, undated (23 letters)
    Biesel, C.: 1931-1933, 1935 (5 items including Christmas cards with original prints)
    Biesel, Frances (Renaissance Society, University of Chicago; see Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Bird, Isabel (Mrs. Paul): 1940, 1942, 1944 (4 letters)
    Bird, Paul: 1938, 1941, 1944, 1945, 1948, 1949 (5 letters)
    Bissell, Julia A. (Mrs. Alfred E.; Wilmington Society of the Fine Arts): 1946
    Bjorkman, Edwin: 1931, 1934, 1941 (3 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Blackie, John Haldam (Vanguard Press): 1928
    Bluemner, Oscar: 1932 (see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files, 1930, 1936)
    Bliss, Betty: 1931, 1933, 1935 (3 items including Christmas card with original print)
    Bloch, E. Maurice: 1949 (3 letters)
    Block, Maurice (Huntington Library): 1938
    Blount, Rose M. (Denver Art Museum): 1934, 1936, 1938-1939, 1941, 1943, 1949 (8 letters)
    Boas, George: 1928
    Boissevain, Engen (see Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Bolander, Karl (Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts): 1928
    Botkin, Henry: 1937
    Bouché, Louis: 1949
    Bowman, Eleanor: 1931 (Christmas card with print)
    Boyce, Ruth: 1930
    Boyer, C. Philip (Mellon Galleries): 1933
    Bransom, Paul: 1938, 1949 (2 letters)
    Bridaham, Lester B. (Strathmont Museum): 1958
    Briggs, Berta N.: 1938
    Britt, George (New York World-Telegram): 1938
    Brodsky, Harold: 1931-1933, 1935-1939, 1943, undated (16 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Brooklyn Museum: 1930, 1957 (4 letters; see also Baur)
    Brown, Adele Smith (Mrs. Philip Stoddard Brown; see Smith, Adele; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Brown, Henry Collins (Museum of the City of New York): 1942
    Brown, Margaret E. (Grace Horne Galleries): 1943-1944 (5 letters)
    Brown, Rollo Walter: 1928
    Bruton, Helen: 1930
    Bufano, Remo: 1928
    Burroughs, Alan: 1928, 1929, 1930, 1937, 1938, 1941 (13 letters)
    Burroughs, Clyde (Detroit Institute of Arts): 1928, 1930, 1938, 1943-1944 (11 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Butler, Roland (Ringling Brothers): 1944
    Call, Mary Bradish and Leigh: 1930, 1932, 1935, 1936 (original Christmas cards)
    Campbell, Heyworth: 1926
    Candler, Duncan: 1927, 1928, 1941 (4 letters)
    Canfield, Cass (Harper and Brothers): 1937, 1947-1948 (5 letters)
    Cantor, Eddie: 1923
    Carlton, Mrs. A.E.: 1952
    Carnegie Institute: 1947, 1948 (2 receipts; see also Kepper, O'Connor, Saint-Gaudens; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Carr, Helen Renne (Mrs. Raymond J. Carr): 1946, 1949 (3 letters)
    Carroll, John: 1938, 1939, 1941 (3 items, including Christmas card with print)
    Carroll, Patricia (Mrs. Anton van Dereck): 1930
    Cashin, Bonnie (typed copy): 1947 (see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Catlin, Mimi (Museum of Modern Art): 1948
    Chapin, Louise V.: 1943-1944 (12 letters)
    Chillman, James (Museum of Fine Arts of Houston): 1928
    Clapp, Frederick Mortimer (The Frick Collection): 1938
    Clark, Virginia and Marshall: 1932-1935 (4 Christmas cards with original prints)
    Clark, Virginia Keep: 1928, 1934 (2 letters)
    Clark, Walter L. (Grand Central Galleries): 1930
    Clear, Charles Val (Akron Art Institute): 1946
    Coates, Dorothy: 1925, 1948 (2 letters)
    Coffin, Robert M. (Art Academy of Cincinnati): 1950-1951 (4 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Cook, Helen Fetter: 1931, 1932, 1936, 1938, 1941-1943 (8 items including Christmas cards)
    Cooper, Gary and Rocky (Mrs. Gary): 1936-1937 (2 letters)
    Connelly, Marc: 1940
    Cosgrave, John O'Hara: 1928, 1938 (2 letters)
    Crocker, Anna B. (Portland Art Association): 1928
    Crowninshield, Frank (Vogue, Art News): 1928, 1932, 1935-1936, 1940-1943, 1946 (13 letters; see also Graham)
    Cuneo, Mrs. Rinaldo: 1938, 1940 (3 letters)
    Cushing, Lily Emmet (Clark Boyd): 1931, 1942, 1945-1948, 1955 (7 letters)
    Cutler, Ann (Hotel Marguery): 1931
    Cutler, Carl Gordon: 1939
    Cutler, Merritt: 1927, 1928, 1942-1945, 1948, 1963 (10 letters)
    Daniel, Harry M.: 1952-1953 (2 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files, 1946)
    Davidson, Alfred: 1945
    Davies Orchards (David Davies): 1928, 1929 (3 letters)
    Davis, Stuart: 1938 (2 letters)
    De Bois, J.H. (Kunsthandel en Antiquariaat, Haarlem): 1938, 1939 (3 letters)
    Dennis, Jan: undated
    Derain, André: 1938
    Diamond, Harry: 1948
    Di Gioia, Frank: 1931, 1933-1948, 1950, 1953, undated (50 items, including original printed Christmas cards)
    Dirks, Rudolph: 1925
    Dorgan, T.A.: 1927
    Dorl, Theodore: 1929, 1931, 1932, 1937, 1938 (9 letters)
    Downs, Mr. and Mrs. Edgar: 1931-1937 (7 Christmas cards with photographs)
    Downtown Gallery (see Halpert and Goldsmith)
    Duckworth, J. Herbert: 1933, 1934 (6 letters)
    Dudensing Galleries Inc. (Richard Dudensing): 1930, 1931, 1932 (4 letters)
    East West Gallery: 1929
    Eggers, George William (Worcester Art Museum, Royal Academy of Art, Stockholm): 1927, 1929 (4 letters)
    Elfers, Herbert (Durand-Ruel, Inc.): 1945, 1947, 1948 (3 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Ellis, Freemont (autograph print, with card from Sally Lewis): [1923]
    Ellsworth, Mary Louise: undated
    Emery, Irene: 1958 (2 letters)
    Ester, Ruth (model): 1944-1945 (6 letters)
    Etchison, Bruce (Washington County Museum of Fine Arts): 1951-1953 (22 letters)
    Evans, Anne (Denver Art Museum): 1933
    Evers, Fred: 1939
    Ferrand, Charles: 1919, 1934, 1937, 1940 (3 letters)
    Findlay, W.C. Jr. (Findlay Galleries): 1939 (2 letters)
    Fischkin, Rose Mary: 1928
    Fitzgerald, George F. (model): 1927, 1933 (2 letters; 1 signed "Man From Eden")
    Fleischman, Doris E.: 1938
    Fliesler, Joseph R.: 1935, 1938, 1949 (3 letters)
    Forbes, Edward (Fogg Art Museum): 1928
    Force, Juliana (Whitney Museum of American Art): 1929, 1932-1937, 1939-1941, 1943 (21 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Fortune (magazine; Deborah Calkins): 1956
    Fox, William Henry: 1923, 1937 (2 letters)
    Francis, Emily O. (Contemporary Arts): 1935
    Francis, Henry Sayles (Cleveland Museum of Art): 1932
    Fraenkel, John: 1934, 1936, 1938, 1939, 1953 (8 letters)
    Frankel, Robert (The Art News): 1939
    Frankenstein, Alfred V. (San Francisco Chronicle): 1940 (2 letters)
    Frankfurter, Alfred M.: 1938, 1945, 1947, 1948, 1950 (10 letters)
    Fraser, Joseph T. (Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts): 1947, 1951 (3 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Free, Karl R.: 1935
    Freeman, Anna (Whitney Museum of American Art): 1938 (2 letters)
    Frey, Erwin F.: 1943, 1945, 1947 (4 letters)
    Frueh, Alfred: 1925, 1953 (2 letters)
    Freund, Frank E.W.: 1932, 1934-1935, 1938 (7 letters)
    Friede, Donald S. (Boni and Liveright Publishers): 1927
    Frink, Angelika W.: 1941 (see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Gallagher, Edward J.: 1952
    Gallatin, Albert E.: 1927, 1928 (3 letters)
    Gardner, Paul (William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art): 1936, 1938-1945, 1947-1950 (26 items including Christmas card with original print; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Gardner, Mrs. William (see Owen)
    Garrett, Garet: 1928
    Garrett, Alice (Mrs. John Work): 1938, 1939 (5 items, including Christmas card with original photograph)
    Gates, Margaret (Studio House, Philips Memorial Gallery): 1935
    Genauer, Emily (New York World Telegram): 1947
    Gest, J.H. (Cincinnati Museum Association): 1928 (3 letters)
    Gise, Margaret (Marie Harriman Gallery): 1938 (see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files and Provenance Files, "Girl in Shako" and "Guide")
    Glackens, William and Edith: 1938
    Glackens, Edith: 1938, 1941, 1943, 1949, 1950 (7 items, including outgoing letters of condolence when William Glackens died, and response from Edith with account of his last day)
    Godwin, Black-More (Toledo Museum of Art): 1932 (2 letters)
    Goldsmith, B.K. (American Print Makers, Downtown Gallery): 1928, 1929, 1930 (3 letters)
    Goldsmith, Morton R.: 1936
    Goodrich, Lloyd (Whitney Museum of American Art; see Provenance Files, "Man with Ship Model")
    Goodyear, A. Conger: 1934, 1938, 1941, 1949 (5 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files, and Provenance Files, "Dryad" and "Man From Eden")
    Goodyear, Mary (Mrs. A. Conger, also Mrs. John W. Ames): 1936-1942, 1947, 1949, 1954 (44 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Grace Horne Galleries (see M.E. Brown, Littlefield; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Graham, John D.: 1937
    Greason, Donald (Deerfield Academy): 1942 (discussing Harry Whitney)
    Grossman, Ted (Edwin Booth): 1938, 1940, 1941, 1945, 1948, 1951, 1952 (13 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Grumman, Paul H. (Joslyn Memorial Art Museum): 1943
    Hagen, Oskar: 1938, 1939 (2 letters)
    Hagerman, Percy (Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center): 1949
    Hale, Dorothea: 1928
    Hale, Robert B. (Metropolitan Museum of Art): 1950-1951 (2 letters)
    Halpert, Edith (Downtown Gallery): 1927, 1928, 1929, 1930 (7 letters; New Year card 1928 printed with collage of Walt Kuhn)
    Hall, Porter: 1941, 1942, 1944, 1948 (4 items, including Christmas card)
    Hanna, Mark: 1942-1944, 1946-1949 (17 letters)
    Hare, Betty (Mrs. Meredith): 1923, 1930-1935, 1939-1941, 1948 (21 letters)
    Harper's Bazaar (see Kaufman, Snow)
    Harriman, Marie: 1946, 1947, 1949, 1958 (4 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Harriman, Mary W.: 1930
    Harriman, W. Averell: 1936, 1937, 1939, 1948, 1949 (5 letters)
    Harrison, Preston: 1928, 1929, 1930 (to Mrs. Harriman), 1933, 1935 (8 letters)
    Harshe, Robert (Art Institute of Chicago): 1928, 1929, 1932 (4 letters)
    Hart, George Overbury "Pop": 1926, 1928, 1929, 1932 (6 letters)
    Hart, Jean Overbury: 1948 (2 letters)
    Hartell, John A. (Cornell University College of Architecture): 1941-1942, 1948 (11 letters)
    Hartley, Marsden: 1937 (2 letters)
    Hartmann, Sadakichi: 1938, 1939-1943 (8 letters, 1940 letter accompanied by ink drawing)
    Harvey, Dorothy Dudley: 1933, 1936 (2 letters)
    Hatch, John Davis Jr. (Albany Institute of History and Art): 1938, 1941 (2 letters)
    Hatfield, Dalzell (Dalzell Hatfield Galleries): 1940
    Haven, Ethel (Museum of Modern Art): 1930 (minutes of board meeting), 1932 (list of names; 2 items; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Hawkins, Frances (Museum of Modern Art): 1943
    Hayes, Helen: 1946
    Heicher, Joyce: 1941
    Heil, Walter (M.H. de Young Memorial Museum): 1943
    Hein Antiques: 1931, undated (4 letters)
    Henry Street Settlement: 1963
    Hess, Thomas: 1953 (Christmas card)
    Heun, Arthur: 1930, 1932-1937, undated (9 items, including Christmas cards)
    Hitchcock, Thomas Jr.: 1927, 1930, 1934-1937, 1939 (7 items, including Christmas cards)
    Hodgson, Daphne: 1931, 1932, 1933, 1936, 1938, 1939 (15 letters)
    Hoffman, Irving: 1947
    Hood, Gretchen: 1928, 1934 (2 letters)
    Hope, Henry R.: 1948, 1951 (3 letters; see also Provenance Files, "Sliced Loaf")
    Howard, Cecil: 1931, 1934, 1936, 1938 (5 letters)
    Howe, Mrs. Frederic: 1931, 1933 (3 letters)
    Howe, Thomas Carr (California Palace of the Legion of Honor): 1947
    Huggins, Wilfrid: 1932
    Hunter, E.R. (Norton Gallery and School of Art): 1947
    Hutchins, Ruth (see Adams)
    Hutton, Ruth: 1931
    Ingersoll, R. Sturgis: 1942, 1944, 1951 (4 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files and Provenance Files, "Young Girl")
    Javis, Sidney (Museum of Modern Art): 1939 (2 letters)
    Jeffreys, Lee: 1931
    Jewell, Edward Alden: 1938
    Jewett, Eleanor (Chicago Tribune): 1928
    Johnson, G.M. (to Vera): 1909 (2 letters)
    Johnston, William: 1927
    Jonson, Raymond: 1938
    Joslyn Memorial Art Museum (see Grumman, Kingman; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Kahn, Otto: 1927, 1928 (2 letters)
    Kaltenbach, G.E. (Art Institute of Chicago): 1931
    Kanzler, Josephine (Mrs. Ernest): 1945, 1947 (3 items including Christmas card)
    Kaufman, Beatrice (Harper's Bazaar): 1935 (2 letters)
    Kaufman, George: 1940
    Keezer, Dexter M. (Reed College): 1936, 1937, 1941, 1945 (6 letters)
    Kelekian, Dikran: 1922-1924, 1933, 1937, undated (9 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Keller, Henry: 1936, 1937, 1938 (3 letters)
    Kennedy, Jacqueline: 1961
    Kenefick, Theodore G.: 1956
    Kennerley, Mitchell (Anderson Galleries, Inc.): 1938, 1941 (4 letters)
    Keppel, Frederick P. (Carnegie Corporation): 1938 (2 letters)
    Kerr, George F. (Society of Illustrators): 1930 (2 letters)
    Kimball, Fiske (The Pennsylvania Museum): 1928, 1939 (2 letters)
    Kingman, Eugene (Joslyn Memorial Art Museum): 1951 (4 letters)
    Kirsch, Dwight (University of Nebraska Department of Art): 1941, 1943-1944, 1946, 1950, 1953 (9 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Kirstein, Lincoln (Museum of Modern Art): 1932
    Kissel, Eleanora: 1928
    Kistler, Aline (San Francisco Chronicle, The San Franciscan, M.H. de Young Memorial Museum): 1929, 1930, 1932, 1933 (6 letters)
    Klopfer, Donald S. (Random House, Inc.): 1940
    Kohl, Dorothy (Philadelphia Art Alliance): 1945 (3 letters)
    Komroff, Manuel: 1938
    Kravis, Hal: 1936, 1941 (3 letters)
    Kunstverein München E.V.: 1930
    Kurtzworth, Harry Muir (Los Angeles Art Association, California Academy of the Fine Arts): 1938 (2 letters)
    Lahr, Bert: 1948 (see also Provenance Files, "Portrait of Bert Lahr")
    Labaudt, Lucien: 1929, 1933, 1936, 1937, 1938 (5 items including Christmas card; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Lamb, James E.: 1928, 1930, 1935, 1937 (4 letters)
    Larcada, Dick: 1963
    Laurent, John: 1947-1950, undated (12 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Laurent, Mimi (Mrs. Robert): 1952
    Laurent, Robert (Indiana University): 1923, 1949, 1953 (8 letters; see also Provenance Files, "Black Butterfly")
    Lea, Lida Gorwin; 1935-1938, 1942 (8 letters, including Christmas card with original print; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Lenssen, Heidi: 1938, 1943, 1947, 1949-1951, 1963, 1964 (9 letters)
    Levy, Adele Rosenwald (Mrs. David M.): 1948
    Lewis, Agnes Knox: 1945
    Lewis, Sally: 1923, 1939 (3 letters, includes signed print by Ellis Freemont; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Lie, Jonas: 1930
    Lindsay, Howard: 1940
    Littlefield, William (Grace Horne's Galleries): 1929
    Liveright, Horace (Boni and Liveright Publishers): 1928
    Lovins, Henry (Hollywood Art Center School): 1938
    Luce, Molly: undated (Christmas card with print)
    Lundgren, Eric: 1947-1953 (61 letters)
    Lustgarten, Samuel (see Provenance Files, "Morning")
    MacFarlane, Janet R. (Albany Institute of History and Art): 1958
    Macnab, Archibald Leavenworth: 1923 (includes typescript of play "The Sculpting of Money"), 1927, 1929 (2 letters)
    MacRae, Elmer: 1939
    Mager, Gus: 1938, 1941-1943, 1946 (9 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Mangravite, Peppino (Cooper Union Art Schools): 1941
    Mann, Margo (model): 1950
    Marie Harriman Gallery (see Harriman, Sardi, Smoluchowska, or Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Matthews, H. L. (The New York Times): 1928
    Matthias, Blanche: 1923, 1927, 1929, 1931-1937, 1940-1941 (19 items, including Christmas cards; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    McBride, Henry: 1935
    McBride, Mary Margaret (WOR radio): 1940
    McCausland, Elizabeth: 1938, 1948 (2 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    McCormick, Chauncey (Art Institute of Chicago): 1938
    McCurdy, Edward: 1928
    McDaniel, Beatrice (Mrs. Bruce): 1940
    McIntyre, Robert: 1931 (2 letters)
    McKim, William: 1945
    Meigs, Ruth Averell (Arden Gallery): 1929 (2 letters)
    Mencken, H.L.: 1945, 1946, 1947 (3 letters; see also Series 4.8: Notes and Writings)
    Merrick, James Kirk (Philadelphia Art Alliance): 1945
    Messer, Thomas M. (American Federation of Arts): 1952-1954 (5 letters)
    Metcalf, Thomas N. (Boston Museum of Modern Art, Inc.): 1938, 1940 (2 letters)
    Metropolitan Museum of Art: 1949, 1956 (5 letters; see also Hale, F.H. Taylor, Wehle)
    Mellon, Minna (Mrs. Paul): 1946
    Millay, Edna St. Vincent (typed copy): 1947 (see also Engen Boissevain in Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Miller, Dorothy C. (Museum of Modern Art): 1943
    Miller, Lulu F. (The Hackley Gallery of Fine Arts): 1928
    Milliken, William M.: 1936 (2 letters)
    Minnigerode, C. Powell (Corcoran Gallery of Art): 1928 (2 letters)
    Montclair Art Museum: 1928, 1932 (2 letters)
    Montgomery, Gertrude: 1928
    More, Hermon (Whitney Museum of American Art): 1933, 1935, 1943, 1948-1950 (8 letters)
    Morgan, Agnes: 1938
    Morison, David (Hamilton Easter Field Art Foundation): 1930
    Morley, Grace: 1936, 1937-1939, 1943 (11 letters; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Morse, John (see Provenance Files, "Man and Sea Beach")
    Muguruza Otaño, Pedro: 1928
    Museum of Art of Ogonquit: 1953 (see also Strater)
    Museum of Modern Art (see Barr, Catlin, Haven, Hawkins, Kirstein, D. Miller, Pelles, A. Porter)
    Nadelman, Viola M. (Mrs. Elie): 1947
    Nankivell, Frank: 1934-1935 (Christmas cards with signed prints)
    National Arts Club: 1932
    Newhall, Beaumont (Museum of Modern Art): 1938
    Nichols, Hobart (National Academy of Design): 1948
    Nichols, J.C. (William Rockhill Nelson Trust): 1948
    North, Henry Ringling (Ringling Brothers): 1941 (2 letters)
    Norton Gallery and School of Art (see Hunter)
    Norton, Ralph H. (Norton Gallery and School of Art): 1948
    O'Connor, John Jr. (Carnegie Institute): 1943, 1945-1946, 1948 (8 letters)
    Oldfield, Otis: 1928-1946, 1948-1949, 1951-1952, undated (111 letters; 1931, 1941, undated include Chritmas cards with print; see also Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    O'Neil, John (University of Oklahoma): 1946
    Owen, Ronnie (Mrs. William Gardner): 1941-1942, 1944-1946, 1948-1949 (15 letters)
    Owens, Virginia B.(Christian Science Monitor): 1943 (2 letters)
    Paley, Goldie (Mrs. Samuel): 1941-1942 (2 letters)
    Pandolfini, Giuseppi: 1938
    Pach, Walter: 1938
    Pascin, Jules: 1921
    Passedoit, Georgete: 1930, 1931, 1932 (3 letters)
    Patterson, Augusta Owen (Town and Country): 1930 (2 letters)
    Paxson, Gordon (Syracuse University School of Art; see Selected Gallery and Exhibition Files)
    Peat, Wilbur D. (John Herron Art Institute): 1944, 1945 (7 letters)
    Pelles, Geraldine (Museum of Modern Art): 1953 (3 letters)
    Pelton, Agnes: 1938
    Penfield, Louis: 1945, 1947-1949 (5 letters)
    Penrose, Julie: 1937, 1948, 1951 (3 letters)
    Perkins, Frances: 1949
    Perls, Klaus G. (Perls Galleries): 1940
    Perrine, Van: 1938
    Perry, Mitzi: 1942
    Petit, Margaret: 1928, 1931-1933, 1935-1938, undated (13 items including Christmas cards)
    Philadelphia Art Alliance (see Kohl, Merrick, Williamson)
    Phillips, Duncan: 1927, 1931, 1932, 1939, 1944 (15 letters)
    Pinchot, Ruth Pickering: 1932
    Poland, Reginald: 1938, 1947-1948 (12 letters)
    Pope, Annemarie (American Federation of Arts): 1951 (5 letters)
    Porter, Allen (Museum of Modern Art): 1945
    Porter, Bruce: 1938
    Potter, Fuller: 1933, 1934, 1936, 1944 (6 items including Christmas card)
    Pratt, Mrs. Harold Irving; 1934 (2 letters, plus notes from lecture)
    Pratt, Julia D.: 1927, 1928 (2 letters)